<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/static-website/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/static-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-07-24T10:11:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/static-website/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Arras Energy</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Arras Energy!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/static-website/jekyll/update/2023/07/20/About_Arras_Energy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Arras Energy!" /><published>2023-07-20T11:59:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-07-20T11:59:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/static-website/jekyll/update/2023/07/20/About_Arras_Energy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/static-website/jekyll/update/2023/07/20/About_Arras_Energy.html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="a-simulation-platform-for-californias-future-electricity-distribution-power-systems">A simulation platform for California’s future electricity distribution power systems.</h3>

<p>GridLAB-D is a research-grade power system simulator developed by the US Department of
Energy and used to study future electricity distribution systems. HiPAS GridLAB-D, rebranded as Arras Energy, is a
commercial-grade high-performance version of this software developed for four California usecases: load electrification, distributed resource integration hosting capacity, tariff design, and
distribution system resilience.</p>

<p>These use-cases address California’s climate change goals,
including electricity infrastructure decarbonization and response to climate change impacts on
electricity distribution system infrastructure.</p>

<p>Arras Energy is as an open-source product available free-of-charge for users, and easily
installed on the most widely used computing platforms. Software support and maintenance
infrastructure is open to contributors and administered by professional software engineers in
consultation with experienced electrical and mechanical engineers.</p>

<p>Key results:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Achieved 97.5% success rate in automatic conversion from Cyme models.</li>
  <li>Simulation speed tests approximately 180 times faster than the DOE version.</li>
  <li>Significant reductions in cloud operating costs, including 94% reduction in storage, and
more than 99% reductions in runtime and computing costs.</li>
</ul>

<p>Linux Foundation Energy, an open-source foundation focused on the power systems sector,
adopted Arras Energy and hosts it within the Linux Foundation’s neutral, collaborative
community to build the shared digital investments that are transforming the world’s
relationship to energy.</p>

<h3 id="background--purpose"><strong>Background &amp; Purpose</strong></h3>
<p>California Investor-Owned Utilities are the owners and operators of distribution systems
serving millions of residential, commercial, industrial, and agricultural customers. By 2016, IOU
spending on distribution systems constituted between 32% and 40% of annual revenue.</p>

<p>Looking ahead, grid modernization efforts which enhance the sensing and automation
capabilities of the distribution system through use of smart grid technologies are projected to
accelerate the size of utility investment in the distribution system.</p>

<p>Customer adoption of
distributed energy resources interconnected into the utility distribution system, climate
stressors such as wildfires and extreme weather, and decarbonization of buildings and
transportation add significant challenges to distribution planning and operation. Utility and
customer actions in response to these challenges underpin the states’ climate policies,
including clean energy adoption goals and resource mandates such as the following:</p>

<ul>
  <li>AB 32, greenhouse gas reduction (GHG) and a cap-and-trade program.</li>
  <li>AB 2514, requires CPUC to determine 
cost-effective energy storage systems by load-serving entities.</li>
  <li>SB 350, Clean Energy and Pollution Reduction Act, 1) expands California’s RPS
goals and requires retail sellers of electricity and local publicly owned electricity to increase procurement of eligible renewable energy resources to 40% by the end of 2024, 45%
by the end of 2027, and 50% by the end of 2030; 2) requires Energy Commission to
establish annual targets for statewide energy efficiency savings in electricity and natural
gas final end uses of retail customers by January 1, 2030; and 3) provides
transformation of Independent System Operator into a regional organization.</li>
  <li>AB 327, requires IOUs to identify optimal locations of DER deployment to
minimize overall system costs and maximize ratepayer benefit from investment in DER.</li>
</ul>

<p>These regulations impact all market segments and all electricity consumers. To achieve these
mandates and other DER goals, California utilities seek more interoperable and efficient tools
to plan and operate the grid. The HiPAS GridLAB-D project has provided the development of a
necessary tool to bring the stakeholders together to support the adoption of mandates and
regulations through modeling and simulation activities.</p>

<h3 id="hipas-gridlab-d-upgrade"><strong>HiPAS GridLAB-D Upgrade</strong></h3>
<p>GridLAB-D is a modern open-source agent-based power system simulation tool developed by
US Department of Energy’s (DOE) Office of Electricity to study modern power systems with
high renewables, energy storage and demand response at the distribution level. GridLAB-D has
been available to the public since 2008. The DOE version of GridLAB-D is highly versatile and
scalable, but it has several important limitations for the use-cases that are common to utilities
serving ratepayers in California. Specifically,</p>
<ol>
  <li>GridLAB-D is difficult to install and deploy in the diverse operating environments found
at utilities in California.</li>
  <li>GridLAB-D requires data that is often difficult to obtain from public sources or is only
available from tools and databases that are proprietary and often difficult to access.</li>
  <li>There are no standard analysis methodologies implemented in GridLAB-D for the
identified use-cases required by California utilities.</li>
  <li>Regulatory agencies need open-source software to perform analyses to consider
distribution and tariff planning questions for renewable integration, energy storage and
demand response.</li>
  <li>GridLAB-D is sometimes too slow and too expensive to run for the kinds of planning
studies needed by larger utilities.</li>
</ol>

<p>This HiPAS project upgraded and augmented the DOE version of GridLAB-D to meet the needs
identified by the user community in California. These included the ability to run large-scale
simulations and analyses on desktop computers, on-premise servers and private clouds, as
well as coordinate a large number of hosted cloud computing assets to complete groups of
simulations that explore a range of scenarios and options. These upgrades have been 
3
integrated into an open-source production release of GridLAB-D that is freely available to the
public.</p>

<h3 id="faster-safer--reliable-results"><strong>Faster, Safer, &amp; Reliable Results</strong></h3>

<p>In 2021 National Grid evaluated HiPAS GridLAB-D as an alternative to the DOE version used
for previous annual 15-year load forecast. The evaluation considered simulation speed,
accuracy of results, and cost of operations as the primary metrics of performance. The study 
required the conversion of approximately 2000 feeder models from Cyme, the import of
historical weather data, and a mapping of load data to network load busses. The simulations
were run for a 1-year horizon, and the results were extrapolated to 15 years using load growth
projections and distributed energy resource adoption rates.</p>

<p>The automatic conversion from Cyme models achieved a 97.5% success rate. The remaining
models had issues that required manual intervention to correct modeling errors that do not
affect Cyme but did affect GridLAB-D simulations. Accuracy was verified by comparing the
2022 simulation results to 2021 and confirming that most of the feeders in 2022 consumed
nearly the same energy or slightly more energy than they did in 2021.</p>

<p>Simulation speed tests comparing HiPAS GridLAB-D to the DOE version showed that the CEC
version is approximately 180 times faster. Key performance indicators for hosting capacity on
the benchmark taxonomy feeders, show that the time to solution (in minutes) as a function of
the network size n (in nodes) in 870n2-83n. The time to solve (in seconds) as a function of the
number of DERs modeled d is 0.57d+2.95. A similar hosting capacity performance test on 476
National Grid feeders shows the time to solution as a function of the number of branches b is
1,080b^2+180b.</p>

<p>Cloud operations costs were also evaluated and compared to the DOE version of GridLAB-D for
the National Grid study. The DOE version required 17 TB of storage, whereas the CEC version
required 1.1 TB of storage, with most of the reduction resulting from corrections to the Cyme
converter, which reduced warning outputs during the simulation. The runtime of the DOE
version required 25,592 hours at an estimated cost of $113,000. After optimization of the
server and simulation, the runtime of the CEC version required a total of 4.5 hours and cost
only $20.25.</p>

<h1 id="learn-more">Learn More</h1>
<p>Check out the <a href="https://google.com">Google</a> for more info on Arras Energy. File all bugs/feature requests at <a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll’s GitHub repo</a>. If you have questions, you can ask them on <a href="https://talk.jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll Talk</a>.</p>

<h1 id="authors">Authors</h1>
<p>Chassin, David P., Alyona I. Teyber, Elizabeth Buechler, Duncan Ragsdale, Matthew Tisdale. 2023. HiPAS GridLAB-D: High-Performance Agent-based Simulation with GridLAB-D.
California Energy Commission. Publication Number: CEC-500-202X-XXX.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A simulation platform for California’s future electricity distribution power systems.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Resources</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/static-website/jekyll/update/2023/07/20/Resources.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Resources" /><published>2023-07-20T11:59:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-07-20T11:59:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/static-website/jekyll/update/2023/07/20/Resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/static-website/jekyll/update/2023/07/20/Resources.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="liturature--reports">Liturature &amp; Reports</h2>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Liturature &amp; Reports]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tutorials</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/static-website/jekyll/update/2023/07/20/Tutorials.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tutorials" /><published>2023-07-20T11:59:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-07-20T11:59:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/static-website/jekyll/update/2023/07/20/Tutorials</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/static-website/jekyll/update/2023/07/20/Tutorials.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="users">Users:</h2>
<ol>
  <li>Students</li>
  <li>researchers</li>
  <li>users</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="developers">Developers:</h2>
<ol>
  <li>Utilities</li>
  <li>manufacturers</li>
  <li>Goverment</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Users: Students researchers users]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Use Cases</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/static-website/jekyll/update/2023/07/20/Use_Cases.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Use Cases" /><published>2023-07-20T11:59:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-07-20T11:59:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/static-website/jekyll/update/2023/07/20/Use_Cases</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/static-website/jekyll/update/2023/07/20/Use_Cases.html"><![CDATA[<p>Arras Energy was developed with four main analysis use-cases in mind, hosting capacity,
tariff design, electrification, and resilience. These use-cases were identified by the Technical
Advisory Committee. In addition, these use-cases provided the basis for additional
requirements, which themselves can be considered more general use-cases for HiPAS GridLABD, giving rise to the following important new features:</p>

<ul>
  <li>CYME model conversion and import.</li>
  <li>Historical, real-time, and forecasted weather.</li>
  <li>AMI and SCADA data import.</li>
  <li>Distribution system assets, such as poles and duct banks.</li>
  <li>Geographic data sets such as address resolution, ground elevation, vegetation, service
territories, census tracts, geographic distances and powerline paths.</li>
  <li>Subcommands to enable internal data and model modification and maintenance
routines.</li>
  <li>Tools to enable external data and model generation and creation capabilities.</li>
  <li>Templates to enable open-source distribution of analysis methodologies.</li>
  <li>Output to plotting modules and cloud-deployed/streaming data repositories.</li>
  <li>Support for cloud-based deployment infrastructure, including Amazon AWS and Docker.</li>
  <li>Support for automated continuous integration and continuous deployment (CI/CA)</li>
  <li>Online documentation for each version deployed.</li>
</ul>

<p>These features result in important new algorithmic, modeling capabilities, and upgrades that
are now a standard part of the GridLAB-D suite of tools distributed in the open-source by the
Linux Foundation Energy (LF Energy) under the brand name “Arras Energy”.</p>

<h3 id="hosting-capacity-analysis"><strong>Hosting Capacity Analysis</strong></h3>
<p>The goal of hosting capacity analysis is to quantify the maximum DER generation, EV charger,
and demand response that can deployed at any location in a distribution network without
violating distribution system voltage, current, or control limits. This process was also referred
to as integration capacity analysis (ICA), particularly when focused only on solar resource
integration.</p>

<p>ICA is achieved using a system-wide iterative power flow solution that examines
all the combinations of loading at every customer meter in a distribution system. Distributed
generation and DER resources are varied at customer meter, independently, to verify whether
a system violation occurs somewhere within a feeder.</p>

<h3 id="grid-resilience-analysis"><strong>Grid Resilience Analysis</strong></h3>
<p>The resilience use-case was supported by the US Department of Energy’s Grid Resilience
Intelligence Project (GRIP) project, funded by the Solar Energy Technology Office. The goal of
GRIP is to assist distribution utilities in responding to grid events by:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Anticipating grid events using machine learning and artificial intelligence techniques
with diverse data sources.</li>
  <li>Absorbing grid events by employing validated control strategies for distributed energy
resources; and</li>
  <li>Reducing recovery time by managing distributed energy resources in the case of limited
communications.</li>
</ul>

<p>GRIP builds on previous efforts to collect massive amounts of data that can be used to finetune grid operations, including the VADER project and other Grid Modernization Lab
Consortium projects on distributed controls and cyber security.</p>

<p>GRIP included innovative applications of artificial intelligence and machine learning for
distribution grid resilience using predictive analytics, image recognition, increased “learning”
and “problem solving” capabilities for anticipation of grid events. The GRIP project
demonstrates distributed control theory with and without communications to absorb and
recover from grid events.</p>

<p>GRIP was deployed, tested and validated with utility partners in North America. Anticipation
analytics were tested and validated with Southern California Edison; absorption algorithms
were tested in Vermont; and extremum seeking controls developed by Lawrence Berkeley
National Laboratory were tested with member utilities of the National Rural Electric
Cooperative Association.</p>

<p>To effectively absorb and recover from grid events a grid resilience model was developed in
HiPAS GridLAB-D, which is coupled with resilience control strategies. HiPAS GridLAB-D code
includes a physical failure model for distribution power poles. Using the physical characteristics
of poles, such as material type, pole size, pole-top equipment specifications and pole design
factors, as well as pole aging information such as age, treatment, maintenance, and general
climate conditions, in conjunction with regional weather data, HiPAS GridLAB-D simulates the
conditions at which a particular pole may fail.</p>

<p>Along with the physical stress and failure model, a degradation model addresses aging of the
poles. An electrical pole is considered at the end of service life by the electrical utility company
when the minimum shell thickness is less than 2 inches. Based on this assumption, the
degradation model uses the difference between the inside and the outside pole’s core moment
at the base of the structure where it is considered weakest. Note that the lifetime of the pole
depends on the geographical location, pole treatment, and the weight of the pole-top
equipment, all of which are described by the pole data and configuration.</p>

<p>Applying the HiPAS GridLAB-D pole model to GRIP resilience studies allows the simulation to
consider the weather vulnerability of the electrical grid based on the electrical network models.
Utility-provided Cyme networks and distribution management system (DMS) control models
are used as test cases to provide realistic network conditions. The implementation of the
electrical feeders starts at substation level and capture components such as transformers,
switches, capacitors, electrical lines and metered loads in the model. These models are loaddriven and data-driven using real-world information from AMI and SCADA systems.</p>

<p>The absorption component of GRIP includes strategies that allow the network to be broken
down into virtual island components using GridLAB-D network modeling capabilities in the
efforts to protect and restore the system, after being exposed to a vulnerability. HiPAS
GridLAB-D allows users to model the conditions when system faults occur and determine
recovery tactics using algorithms developed by Packetized Energy. Using this feature, a power
system failure is simulated because of an extreme event, such as high wind, which breaks the
network into isolated islands. The networks are assumed to be equipped with solar and battery
technology to support the generation requirements within a virtual network island as seen in Figure 1, below.</p>

<p>The topology employs large switching devices under specific control strategies 
that disconnects portions of the grid based on the location of the fault or system vulnerability. \Figure 1.</p>

<p><strong>Figure 1. Virtual islanding capability for GRIP’s absorption algorithm developed by Packetized Energy.</strong></p>

<h3 id="electrification"><strong>Electrification</strong></h3>
<p>Electrification analysis examines the impact of converting customer end-uses provided by 
natural gas, heating oil, or other fossil-energy sources to electricity. In residential buildings, 
the end-uses that may be converted include heating, cooking, water-heating, and clothes 
drying. The simulation delivers feeder-level load shapes as the fraction of converted end-uses 
is increased. In addition, the residential building model identifies when the capacity of the 
distribution panel in the home is exceeded, and a panel upgrade is required.</p>

<h3 id="tariff-analysis"><strong>Tariff Analysis</strong></h3>
<p>The tariff analysis use-case is designed to include a few tariff structures that IOUs, POUs and 
CCAs implement to give HiPAS GridLAB-D users the ability to explore a variety of tariff designs 
for their distribution networks and customer compositions. Tariff models are obtained from the 
National Renewable Energy Laboratory (NREL) OpenEI database of tariffs. These include 
recent tariff data for the following utilities.</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Investor-Owned Utilities</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Bear Valley Electric Service</li>
      <li>Pacific Gas and Electric</li>
      <li>PacifiCorp</li>
      <li>San Diego Gas and Electric</li>
      <li>Southern California Edison (SCE)</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Publicly Owned LSEs Including Publicly Owned Utilities (POUs)</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Alameda Municipal Power</li>
      <li>City of Anaheim</li>
      <li>Azusa Light and Water</li>
      <li>City of Banning</li>
      <li>Biggs Municipal Utilities</li>
      <li>Burbank Water and Power</li>
      <li>CCSF (also called the Power Enterprise of the San Francisco Public Utilities Commission)</li>
      <li>City of Cerritos, Cerritos Electric Utility</li>
      <li>City of Industry</li>
      <li>Colton Public Utilities</li>
      <li>City of Corona</li>
      <li>Eastside Power Authority</li>
      <li>Glendale Water and Power</li>
      <li>Gridley Electric Utility</li>
      <li>City of Healdsburg</li>
      <li>Imperial Irrigation District (IID)</li>
      <li>Kirkwood Meadows Public Utility District</li>
      <li>Lassen Municipal Utility District</li>
      <li>Lathrop Irrigation District</li>
      <li>Lodi Electric Utility</li>
      <li>City of Lompoc</li>
      <li>Los Angeles Department of Water &amp; Power (LADWP)</li>
      <li>Merced Irrigation District (MeID)</li>
      <li>Modesto Irrigation District (MID)</li>
      <li>Moreno Valley Utility (MVU)</li>
      <li>City of Needles (Public Utility Authority)</li>
      <li>City of Palo Alto</li>
      <li>Pasadena Water and Power</li>
      <li>City of Pittsburg, Pittsburg Power Company Island Energy</li>
      <li>Port of Oakland</li>
      <li>Port of Stockton</li>
      <li>Power and Water Resources Pooling Authority (PWRPA)</li>
      <li>Rancho Cucamonga Municipal Utility</li>
      <li>Redding Electric Utility</li>
      <li>City of Riverside</li>
      <li>Roseville Electric</li>
      <li>Sacramento Municipal Utility District (SMUD)</li>
      <li>City of Shasta Lake</li>
      <li>Shelter Cove Resort Improvement District</li>
      <li>Silicon Valley Power (SVP)</li>
      <li>Trinity Public Utilities District (PUD)</li>
      <li>Truckee Donner Public Utilities District</li>
      <li>Turlock Irrigation District (TID)</li>
      <li>City of Ukiah</li>
      <li>City of Vernon</li>
      <li>Victorville Municipal Utilities Services</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h1 id="additional-use-cases">Additional Use Cases</h1>
<ul>
  <li>Hosting Capacity Analysis</li>
  <li>Grid Resilience Analysis</li>
  <li>Electrification</li>
  <li>Tariff Analysis</li>
</ul>

<p>These prove how efficent and easily applicable the new HiPAS GRIDLAB-D is</p>

<p>Check out the <a href="https://google.com">Google</a> for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at <a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll’s GitHub repo</a>. If you have questions, you can ask them on <a href="https://talk.jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll Talk</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arras Energy was developed with four main analysis use-cases in mind, hosting capacity, tariff design, electrification, and resilience. These use-cases were identified by the Technical Advisory Committee. In addition, these use-cases provided the basis for additional requirements, which themselves can be considered more general use-cases for HiPAS GridLABD, giving rise to the following important new features:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/static-website/jekyll/update/2023/07/20/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2023-07-20T11:59:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-07-20T11:59:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/static-website/jekyll/update/2023/07/20/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/static-website/jekyll/update/2023/07/20/welcome-to-jekyll.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="is-this-working">Is this working?????</h1>

<p>You’ll find this post in your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll serve</code>, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</p>

<p>Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP</code></p>

<p>Where <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR</code> is a four-digit number, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MONTH</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">DAY</code> are both two-digit numbers, and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MARKUP</code> is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.</p>

<p>Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">"Hi, </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">"</span>
<span class="k">end</span>
<span class="n">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">'Tom'</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="c1">#=&gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Check out the <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home">Jekyll docs</a> for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at <a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll’s GitHub repo</a>. If you have questions, you can ask them on <a href="https://talk.jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll Talk</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is this working?????]]></summary></entry></feed>